#### Contact

5099399840 (Mobile) kaliclark122@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kali-daytonagacnp-bc-dnp-a60726117 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Spanish Nursing Acute Care

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner Registered Nurse

# Kali Dayton, AGACNP-BC, DNP

Critical Care Nurse Practitioner Host of the podcast "Walking Home From the ICU" Tele-Critical Care

Salt Lake City, Utah

## Summary

I have my doctorate degree as an Acute Care Nurse Practitioner (ACNP) and work in the ICU as an ACNP. My expertise includes early mobility, delirium prevention, and sedation management in the ICU. I specialize in ICU care that restores patient's lives in all aspects.

As a legal nurse consultant, I specialize in medical record review, standard of care, expert witness, nursing negligence, malpractice, personal injury, nurse defense, and wrongful death. I am seeking to use my expertise to help with your difficult and interesting legal cases.

I have 6 years of intensive care unit (ICU) experience as a Registered Nurse. I have worked at 7 different hospitals in 4 states. My areas of critical care experience include: medical, surgical, trauma, thoracic, cardiovascular, respiratory, and neuro. I am also available as a patient and family advocate. I am able to translate the most complicated medical rhetoric into simple english/spanish terms for the layman.

# Experience

Salt Lake City Corporation
Critical Care Nurse Practitioner
August 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Salt Lake City, UT

Self-empolyed contractor Expert Witness / Legal Nurse Consultant November 2015 - Present (4 years 8 months)

I specialize in medical record review of wrongful death, personal injury, malpractice, nurse negligence, and nurse defense.

Legal Nurse Consultant Legal Nurse Consultant September 2015 - Present (4 years 10 months)

Specialize in Acute Care and Intensive Care cases

LDS Hospital RN in MSICU August 2015 - Present (4 years 11 months) Salt Lake City, UT

Deaconess Hospital RN in Cardiac/MSICU April 2015 - August 2015 (5 months) Spokane, WA

Inova Fairfax Hospital Travel RN in Neuroscience ICU December 2014 - April 2015 (5 months) Fairfax, VA

Also worked as float RN to Trauma ICU

Aroostook County Hospital Travel RN in MSICU April 2014 - August 2014 (5 months) Presque Isle, ME

Intermountain- LDS Hospital RN in MSICU April 2012 - April 2014 (2 years 1 month) Salt Lake City, UT

# Education

University of Utah

Doctorate of Acute Care Gerontology Nurse Practitioner · (2015 - 2018)